Ed:
Did you make notes while you were watching the performances of Romeo
and Juliet, Gemma?
Gemma:
Yes, I did.
I found it quite hard though.
I kept getting too involved in the play.
Ed:
Me too.
I ended up not taking notes.
I wrote down my impressions when I got home.
Do you mind if I check a few things with you?
In case I’ve missed anything.
And I’ve also got some questions about our assignment.
Gemma:
No, it’s good to talk things through.
I may have missed things too.
Ed:
OK great.
So first of all, I’m not sure how much information we should include in
our reviews.
Gemma:
Right.
Well, I don’t think we need to describe what happens.
Especially as Romeo and Juliet is one of Shakespeare’s most well-known plays.
Ed:
Yeah, everyone knows the story.
In an essay we’d focus on the poetry and Shakespeare’s use of imagery
etc.,
but that isn’t really relevant in a review.
We’re supposed to focus on how effective this particular production is.
Gemma:
Mmm.
We should say what made it a success or a failure.
Ed:
And part of that means talking about the emotional impact the performance had on
us.
I think that’s important.
Gemma:
Yes.
And we should definitely mention how well the director handled important bits of the
play – like when Romeo climbs onto Juliet’s balcony.
Ed:
And the fight between Mercutio and Tybalt.
Gemma:
Yes.
It would also be interesting to mention the theatre space and how the director used it
but I don’t think we’ll have space in 800 words.
Ed:
No.
OK.
That all sounds quite straightforward.
Ed:
So what about The Emporium Theatre’s production of the play?
Gemma:
I thought some things worked really well but there were some problems too.
Ed:
Yeah.
What about the set, for example?
Gemma:
I think it was visually really stunning.
I’d say that was probably the most memorable thing about this production.
Ed:
You’re right.
The set design was really amazing,
but actually I have seen similar ideas used in other productions.
Gemma:
What about the lighting?
Some of the scenes were so dimly lit it was quite hard to see.
Ed:
I didn’t dislike it.
It helped to change the mood of the quieter scenes.
Gemma:
That’s a good point.
Ed:
What did you think of the costumes?
Gemma:
I was a bit surprised by the contemporary dress, I must say.
Ed:
Yeah – I think it worked well,
but I had assumed it would be more conventional.
Gemma:
Me too.
I liked the music at the beginning and I thought the musicians were brilliant,
but I thought they were wasted because the music didn’t have much impact in Acts 2
and 3.
Ed:
Yes – that was a shame.
Gemma:
One problem with this production was that the actors didn’t deliver the lines that
well.
They were speaking too fast.
Ed:
It was a problem I agree,
but I thought it was because they weren’t speaking loudly enough – especially at
key points in the play.
Gemma:
I actually didn’t have a problem with that.
Ed:
It’s been an interesting experience watching different versions of Romeo
and Juliet, hasn’t it?
Gemma:
Definitely.
It’s made me realise how relevant the play still is.
Ed:
Right.
I mean a lot’s changed since Shakespeare’s time,
but in many ways nothing’s changed.
There are always disagreements and tension between teenagers and their parents.
Gemma:
Yes,
that’s something all young people can relate to – more than the violence
and the extreme emotions in the play.
Ed:
How did you find watching it in translation?
Gemma:
Really interesting.
I expected to find it more challenging,
but I could follow the story pretty well.
Ed:
I stopped worrying about not being able to understand all the words
and focused on the actors’ expressions.
The ending was pretty powerful.
Gemma:
Yes.
That somehow intensified the emotion for me.
Ed:
Did you know Shakespeare’s been translated into more languages than any other writer?
Gemma:
What’s the reason for his international appeal, do you think?
Ed:
I was reading that it’s because his plays are about basic themes that people
everywhere are familiar with.
Gemma:
Yeah,
and they can also be understood on different levels.
The characters have such depth.
Ed:
Right – which allows directors to experiment and find new angles.
Gemma:
That’s really important because …